export const chapter = "Chapter - 7: The Mughal Policy ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What was the main source of information about Akbar's rule?",
        optionA: "Tuzuk-i-Jahangiri",
        optionB: "Ain-i-Akbari",
        optionC: "Akbarnama",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In which volume of Akbarnama is the information about Akbar's administration found?",
        optionA: "Volume 1",
        optionB: "Volume 2",
        optionC: "Volume 3 (Ain-i-Akbari)",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the primary purpose of the diwan-i-khas in the Mughal royal court?",
        optionA: "Meeting common people",
        optionB: "Reading out reports",
        optionC: "Meeting nobles and officers",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which department in the Mughal administration was responsible for revenue, income, and expenditure?",
        optionA: "Wazir",
        optionB: "Mir Bakshi",
        optionC: "Sadr-i-Sadur",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the primary source of income for a ruler during the Mughal period?",
        optionA: "Trade",
        optionB: "Land revenue",
        optionC: "Taxes on pilgrimage",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who developed the system of Todar Mal's bandobast for fixing land revenue?",
        optionA: "Akbar",
        optionB: "Aurangzeb",
        optionC: "Todar Mal",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the key feature of the Mughal military administration called mansabdari?",
        optionA: "Hereditary positions",
        optionB: "Fixed land grants",
        optionC: "Rank system",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How did the Mughal ruler control an army without being dependent on any mansabdar?",
        optionA: "Diplomacy",
        optionB: "Maintaining a navy",
        optionC: "Direct control",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What factor caused issues in the efficiency of the mansabdari system during Aurangzeb's time?",
        optionA: "Military campaigns",
        optionB: "Suppression of non-Muslims",
        optionC: "Land revenue system",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How did Akbar treat the Rajputs after conquering them, as mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Humiliation",
        optionB: "Exile",
        optionC: "Honourably and with high posts",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Akbar became a popular ruler on the basis of his policies of ________ and tolerance.",
        options: ["suppression", "harmony", "military conquest"],
        correctAnswer: "harmony",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Aurangzeb grew unpopular because he followed the policies of suppressing the ________, which shrank his empire.",
        options: ["nobles", "non-Muslims", "merchants"],
        correctAnswer: "non-Muslims",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The main source of information about Akbar's rule is the ________, his biography.",
        options: ["Tuzuk-i-Jahangiri", "Ain-i-Akbari", "Akbarnama"],
        correctAnswer: "Akbarnama",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mughal ruler generally sat at two places: diwan-i-khas to meet nobles and officers, and diwan-i-aam to meet ________.",
        options: ["common people", "merchants", "foreign dignitaries"],
        correctAnswer: "common people",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The empire was divided into subas (provinces), each under the charge of a ________.",
        options: ["kotwal", "sadr-i-sadur", "subadar"],
        correctAnswer: "subadar",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Revenue during the Mughal period was charged on trade, crafts, and cultivation. In addition, taxes were charged on activities such as pilgrimage, jaziya, and construction of ________.",
        options: ["houses", "roads", "bridges"],
        correctAnswer: "houses",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Land revenue (from cultivation) was fixed at ________ during Akbar's time.",
        options: ["one-fourth", "one-third", "one-half"],
        correctAnswer: "one-third",
      },
      {
        question:
          "An important feature of the Mughal administration was mansabdari or ________ system.",
        options: ["feudal", "rank", "hereditary"],
        correctAnswer: "rank",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mughals made use of cannons and gunpowder during military campaigns, which overawed the ________.",
        options: ["nobles", "adversary", "common people"],
        correctAnswer: "adversary",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Diplomacy is an important part of administration; a ruler's efficiency depends on how he maintains relations with other rulers. When Akbar conquered the Rajputs, he treated them honourably and gave them high posts in his administration. This helped him have friendly relations with the ________.",
        options: ["Persians", "Mughals", "Rajputs"],
        correctAnswer: "Rajputs",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Akbar's policies of harmony and tolerance contributed to the expansion and prosperity of his empire.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Aurangzeb's policies of suppressing non-Muslims led to the growth and stability of his empire.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The main source of information about Akbar's rule is the Tuzuk-i-Jahangiri.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The diwan-i-khas was the hall of public audience in the Mughal royal court.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The empire was divided into provinces, each under the charge of a sadr-i-sadur.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "During the Mughal period, taxes were charged on activities such as pilgrimage, jaziya, and construction of houses.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Land revenue from cultivation was fixed at one-half during Akbar's time.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The mansabdari system in the Mughal administration was hereditary.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "The Mughals maintained a strong navy during their rule.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Akbar's diplomatic policy towards the Rajputs involved treating them honourably and giving them high posts in his administration.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
